

Patricia McPhee

TECHNICAL WRITER
CONTENT DEVELOPER

Broomfield, CO hi@patriciamcphee.com www.patriciamcphee.work

About Me

I have 25 years of experience creating scenario and goal-based content to help IT professionals achieve more with technology. I'm passionate about bringing stale or unusable content back to life by taking the guesswork out of complex technical content.

Education

10/2010 - 05/2012 Kaplan University

BS in Health Science (public and environmental health)

02/1999 - 04/2001 **DeVry University - Denver**

AS Computer Systems (networking and telecommunications)

Work Experience

05/2020 - Pres.

Content Developer, Contractor

Microsoft/Kforce

Work collaboratively with the Azure VMware Solution core engineering and UX Research teams to develop scenario and goal-based content. Conduct content audits of existing content to identify areas for improvement. Use qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2019 - 06/2021

Freelance

- Extreme Networks (2020 2021) Reviewed and edited network hardware content for the FIPS program. Wrote shell scripts to automate API content publishing.
- Netdata (2020) Wrote product content for a Linux server performance tool.
- **ZPE Systems (2019-2020)** Wrote a marketing campaign eBook on automating the data center. Wrote video scripts, provided the voiceover, and produced how-to videos.
- Wax.io (2019) Contributed to blockchain blog articles.

03/2019 - 06/2019

Technical Writer II

LivePerson

Wrote SDK and API guides for mobile messaging app.

01/2018 - 01/2019

Technical Writer II

Microsoft

Worked collaboratively with the Microsoft Edge and Windows networking core teams. Conducted content audits to identify areas for potential improvement. Used qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2017 - 12/2017

Technical Writer, Contractor

Oculus/Facebook

Developed internal cross-functional workflows and process documentation for a virtual reality R&D environment.

08/2016 - 05/2017

Software Technical Writer

GE Healthcare

Worked collaboratively with customers and support to update the outdated installation and upgrade guides. The rework resulted in more successful upgrades and reduced customer support calls.



Skills

Technical Writing

Content Strategy

UX/UI Writing

Information Architecture

Project Management

Instructional Design

Markdown

Git/GitHub

Agile/Jira/Azure DevOps

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Premiere Pro

Voiceover

Video Production

MadCap Flare

DITA/XLM

Jekyll (static site generator)

Work Experience

09/2015 - 07/2016

Technical Writer II

Amazon

Wrote internal feature announcements and task-oriented procedure guides for warehouse employees.

03/2015 - 09/2015

Technical Writer, Contractor

Charter Communications

Worked collaboratively with video-on-demand and networking engineers to write standard procedures. Wrote Python scripts for system administration tasks.

01/2014 - 10/2014

Technical Writer

SolidFire, a NetApp company

Wrote release notes, configuration and troubleshooting guides, white papers, and solution briefs for the cloud storage solution.

12/2012 - 12/2013

Technical Writer, Contractor

Sybase/SAP

Wrote installation, configuration, and API guides for a mobile money app.

07/2012 - 01/2013

Technical Writer, Contractor

CarpeDatum

Wrote design specifications and instructor-led training guides for enterprise planning and budgeting software.

08/2011 - 07/2012

Technical Writer, Contractor

Level 3 Communications, a CenturyLink company

Wrote fiber optic provisioning procedures for field technicians.

Achievements

- Wrote shell scripts to automate API content publishing.
- Built custom MadCap Flare authoring environment for GE Healthcare, Amazon, and SolidFire. Converted legacy documentation created in Microsoft Word to maximize content reuse and reduce the cost of creating, managing, and publishing content.
- Co-authoried Excel 2010 in Simple Steps. ISBN: 0-27-373613-2